<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rootTag>
<Award>
<AwardTitle>Fulfilling the Atomic Physics Needs for Spectral Diagnostics of Cosmic Chemical Evolution</AwardTitle>
<AwardEffectiveDate>09/01/2020</AwardEffectiveDate>
<AwardExpirationDate>08/31/2023</AwardExpirationDate>
<AwardTotalIntnAmount>299525.00</AwardTotalIntnAmount>
<AwardAmount>299525</AwardAmount>
<AwardInstrument>
<Value>Standard Grant</Value>
</AwardInstrument>
<Organization>
<Code>03020000</Code>
<Directorate>
<Abbreviation>MPS</Abbreviation>
<LongName>Direct For Mathematical &amp; Physical Scien</LongName>
</Directorate>
<Division>
<Abbreviation>AST</Abbreviation>
<LongName>Division Of Astronomical Sciences</LongName>
</Division>
</Organization>
<ProgramOfficer>
<SignBlockName>Harshal Gupta</SignBlockName>
</ProgramOfficer>
<AbstractNarration>Understanding the evolution of chemical elements in the Universe is crucial for understanding the evolution of galaxies.  Optical spectra of atoms and ions known as damped Lyman-alpha (DLA) absorbers observed against background quasars and gamma-ray burst (GRB) afterglows represent the most sensitive tools to measure elemental abundances in distant galaxies.  This project will generate accurate and reliable data required to derive elemental abundances from DLA absorbers, allowing astronomers to interpret observations of distant galaxies and test models of chemical evolution.  The project will train graduate and undergraduate students in astrophysical research, provide research experience to high school students, as well as engage a diverse population through astronomy outreach activities.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Using high-level theoretical atomic physics methods, the research team will calculate oscillator strengths for optical transitions of key DLA and sub-DLA absorbers.  The team will then test the reliability of the calculated data by benchmarking them against high-quality astronomical spectra in conjunction with photoionization modeling.  By enabling accurate interpretation of large-scale spectroscopic observations of high-redshift quasars, GRBs, and star-forming galaxies, this project will help advance our understanding of the chemical evolution of galaxies.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This award reflects NSF's statutory mission and has been deemed worthy of support through evaluation using the Foundation's intellectual merit and broader impacts review criteria.</AbstractNarration>
<MinAmdLetterDate>07/30/2020</MinAmdLetterDate>
<MaxAmdLetterDate>07/30/2020</MaxAmdLetterDate>
<ARRAAmount/>
<AwardID>2009811</AwardID>
<Investigator>
<FirstName>Varsha</FirstName>
<LastName>Kulkarni</LastName>
<EmailAddress>kulkarni@sc.edu</EmailAddress>
<StartDate>07/30/2020</StartDate>
<EndDate/>
<RoleCode>Principal Investigator</RoleCode>
</Investigator>
<Institution>
<Name>University of South Carolina at Columbia</Name>
<CityName>COLUMBIA</CityName>
<ZipCode>292080001</ZipCode>
<PhoneNumber>8037777093</PhoneNumber>
<StreetAddress>Sponsored Awards Management</StreetAddress>
<CountryName>United States</CountryName>
<StateName>South Carolina</StateName>
<StateCode>SC</StateCode>
</Institution>
<ProgramElement>
<Code>1216</Code>
<Text>GALACTIC ASTRONOMY PROGRAM</Text>
</ProgramElement>
<ProgramReference>
<Code>1205</Code>
<Text>LABORATORY ASTROPHYSICS</Text>
</ProgramReference>
<ProgramReference>
<Code>1206</Code>
<Text>THEORETICAL &amp; COMPUTATIONAL ASTROPHYSICS</Text>
</ProgramReference>
<ProgramReference>
<Code>1207</Code>
<Text>OBSERVATIONAL ASTRONOMY</Text>
</ProgramReference>
<ProgramReference>
<Code>7480</Code>
<Text>ARCHIVAL DATA ANALYSIS</Text>
</ProgramReference>
<ProgramReference>
<Code>9150</Code>
<Text>EXP PROG TO STIM COMP RES</Text>
</ProgramReference>
</Award>
</rootTag>
