<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rootTag>
<Award>
<AwardTitle>Targeted Infusion Project: Developing the Biotechnology Certificate Program at Harris-Stowe State University</AwardTitle>
<AwardEffectiveDate>08/15/2020</AwardEffectiveDate>
<AwardExpirationDate>07/31/2023</AwardExpirationDate>
<AwardTotalIntnAmount>342699.00</AwardTotalIntnAmount>
<AwardAmount>342699</AwardAmount>
<AwardInstrument>
<Value>Standard Grant</Value>
</AwardInstrument>
<Organization>
<Code>11060000</Code>
<Directorate>
<Abbreviation>EHR</Abbreviation>
<LongName>Direct For Education and Human Resources</LongName>
</Directorate>
<Division>
<Abbreviation>HRD</Abbreviation>
<LongName>Division Of Human Resource Development</LongName>
</Division>
</Organization>
<ProgramOfficer>
<SignBlockName>Emanuel WAddell</SignBlockName>
</ProgramOfficer>
<AbstractNarration>The Historically Black Colleges and Universities Undergraduate Program (HBCU-UP) through Targeted Infusion Projects supports the development, implementation, and study of evidence-based innovative models and approaches for improving the preparation and success of HBCU undergraduate students so that they may pursue STEM graduate programs and/or careers. This project at Harris-Stowe State University will develop a Biotechnology Certificate for STEM students that will provide a skill set which they may use to gain employment in the St. Louis Biotechnology environment.    &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The proposed work intends to use CURES (Classroom Undergraduate Research Experiences) to achieve three aims. The first aim is to develop advanced laboratory courses to support a biotechnology certificate program. The second aim is to establish the biotechnology certificate at Harris-Stowe State University. The third aim is to provide CURES that will increase workplace readiness and opportunity placement for students. The implementation of CURES will assist students in developing critical thinking skills, project management and tolerance for ambiguity. The proposed implementation at Harris-Stowe State University will broaden the participation of underrepresented minorities in the STEM workforce. Students who successfully complete the program will be granted a biotechnology certificate that will provide them with a competitive advantage in pursuing STEM opportunities such as graduate school employment and internships.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This award reflects NSF's statutory mission and has been deemed worthy of support through evaluation using the Foundation's intellectual merit and broader impacts review criteria.</AbstractNarration>
<MinAmdLetterDate>08/07/2020</MinAmdLetterDate>
<MaxAmdLetterDate>08/07/2020</MaxAmdLetterDate>
<ARRAAmount/>
<AwardID>2011870</AwardID>
<Investigator>
<FirstName>Sandra</FirstName>
<LastName>Leal</LastName>
<EmailAddress>leals@hssu.edu</EmailAddress>
<StartDate>08/07/2020</StartDate>
<EndDate/>
<RoleCode>Co-Principal Investigator</RoleCode>
</Investigator>
<Investigator>
<FirstName>Scott</FirstName>
<LastName>Horrell</LastName>
<EmailAddress>horrells@hssu.edu</EmailAddress>
<StartDate>08/07/2020</StartDate>
<EndDate/>
<RoleCode>Principal Investigator</RoleCode>
</Investigator>
<Investigator>
<FirstName>Rekha</FirstName>
<LastName>Meyer</LastName>
<EmailAddress>meyerre@hssu.edu</EmailAddress>
<StartDate>08/07/2020</StartDate>
<EndDate/>
<RoleCode>Co-Principal Investigator</RoleCode>
</Investigator>
<Investigator>
<FirstName>Carmel</FirstName>
<LastName>Martin-Fairey</LastName>
<EmailAddress>martinca@hssu.edu</EmailAddress>
<StartDate>08/07/2020</StartDate>
<EndDate/>
<RoleCode>Co-Principal Investigator</RoleCode>
</Investigator>
<Institution>
<Name>Harris Stowe State College</Name>
<CityName>Saint Louis</CityName>
<ZipCode>631032136</ZipCode>
<PhoneNumber>3143403544</PhoneNumber>
<StreetAddress>3026 Laclede Avenue</StreetAddress>
<CountryName>United States</CountryName>
<StateName>Missouri</StateName>
<StateCode>MO</StateCode>
</Institution>
<ProgramElement>
<Code>1594</Code>
<Text>Hist Black Colleges and Univ</Text>
</ProgramElement>
<ProgramReference>
<Code>9178</Code>
<Text>UNDERGRADUATE EDUCATION</Text>
</ProgramReference>
</Award>
</rootTag>
