<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rootTag>
<Award>
<AwardTitle>SBIR Phase I:  Neurocognitive and behavioral detection of THC impairment</AwardTitle>
<AwardEffectiveDate>09/01/2020</AwardEffectiveDate>
<AwardExpirationDate>08/31/2021</AwardExpirationDate>
<AwardTotalIntnAmount>224472.00</AwardTotalIntnAmount>
<AwardAmount>224472</AwardAmount>
<AwardInstrument>
<Value>Standard Grant</Value>
</AwardInstrument>
<Organization>
<Code>07070000</Code>
<Directorate>
<Abbreviation>ENG</Abbreviation>
<LongName>Directorate For Engineering</LongName>
</Directorate>
<Division>
<Abbreviation>IIP</Abbreviation>
<LongName>Div Of Industrial Innovation &amp; Partnersh</LongName>
</Division>
</Organization>
<ProgramOfficer>
<SignBlockName>Alastair Monk</SignBlockName>
</ProgramOfficer>
<AbstractNarration>The broader/commercial impact of this Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) Phase I project is to develop a reliable tool for law enforcement for the detection of cannabis-related driving impairment. Impaired operation of equipment costs the nation hundreds of billions of dollars annually. Our detection tool is a software application designed to be presented on a mobile tablet device. It will utilize a combination of neurocognitive, behavioral, and physiological indicators of cannabis intoxication to make an informed determination of impairment. This detection tool may be used as a roadside device by law enforcement, as a screening tool by employers of transit companies, or by an individual user. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) Phase I project is to develop a portable mobile device and software to perform a roadside cannabis detection test. The software will perform a rapid sequence of neuropsychological tests.  Combined with an infrared camera to track eye movement and pupillary reflex during driver evaluation, this system can potentially detect driving impairment due to tetrahydrocannabinol. A machine learning algorithm will be used to both assess physical and neurological test results and to present a progressive testing architecture.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This award reflects NSF's statutory mission and has been deemed worthy of support through evaluation using the Foundation's intellectual merit and broader impacts review criteria.</AbstractNarration>
<MinAmdLetterDate>06/24/2020</MinAmdLetterDate>
<MaxAmdLetterDate>06/24/2020</MaxAmdLetterDate>
<ARRAAmount/>
<AwardID>2014649</AwardID>
<Investigator>
<FirstName>Ari</FirstName>
<LastName>Kirshenbaum</LastName>
<EmailAddress>arikirshenbaum@icloud.com</EmailAddress>
<StartDate>06/24/2020</StartDate>
<EndDate/>
<RoleCode>Principal Investigator</RoleCode>
</Investigator>
<Institution>
<Name>DRIVEABILITY VT, LLC</Name>
<CityName>BURLINGTON</CityName>
<ZipCode>054082608</ZipCode>
<PhoneNumber>8025789322</PhoneNumber>
<StreetAddress>71 CRESCENT BEACH DR</StreetAddress>
<CountryName>United States</CountryName>
<StateName>Vermont</StateName>
<StateCode>VT</StateCode>
</Institution>
<ProgramElement>
<Code>5371</Code>
<Text>SBIR Phase I</Text>
</ProgramElement>
<ProgramReference>
<Code>8033</Code>
<Text>Hardware Software Integration</Text>
</ProgramReference>
</Award>
</rootTag>
