<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rootTag>
<Award>
<AwardTitle>SBIR Phase I:  Development of point-of-care diagnostics to direct the appropriate use of antibiotics for the treatment of high-risk urinary tract infections</AwardTitle>
<AwardEffectiveDate>05/01/2020</AwardEffectiveDate>
<AwardExpirationDate>04/30/2021</AwardExpirationDate>
<AwardTotalIntnAmount>224996.00</AwardTotalIntnAmount>
<AwardAmount>224996</AwardAmount>
<AwardInstrument>
<Value>Standard Grant</Value>
</AwardInstrument>
<Organization>
<Code>07070000</Code>
<Directorate>
<Abbreviation>ENG</Abbreviation>
<LongName>Directorate For Engineering</LongName>
</Directorate>
<Division>
<Abbreviation>IIP</Abbreviation>
<LongName>Div Of Industrial Innovation &amp; Partnersh</LongName>
</Division>
</Organization>
<ProgramOfficer>
<SignBlockName>Henry Ahn</SignBlockName>
</ProgramOfficer>
<AbstractNarration>This Small Business Innovation Research Phase I project will provide critical development of a rapid diagnostic test capable of delivering the antibiotic resistance profile of a sample collected from patients suspected of suffering from urinary tract infections (UTIs). In the US there are approximately 8 million UTIs, and an increasing number of are caused by drug-resistant bacteria that significantly complicate the treatment of these infections. In general, patients suffering from a drug resistant UTI take longer to receive appropriate treatment, resulting in a greater risk of disease progression and onset of secondary comorbidities.  Diagnostic tests that can rapidly identify drug-resistant UTIs will have a strong and positive impact on the treatment of these infections. The proposed work aims to optimize and expand the diagnostic capacity of a first-generation diagnostic assay to create a fully comprehensive test that can detect a drug-resistant UTI in minutes.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;The proposed SBIR Phase I project will advance the development of a dual-enzyme trigger-enabled cascade technology (DETECT), developed to detect low-abundant beta-lactamases produced by uropathogens to hydrolyze beta-lactamase antibiotics, rendering them ineffective. The presence of beta-lactamase-producing uropathogens can greatly complicate clinical decision-making because these pathogens are regularly resistant to the first-line antibiotics considered for treatment of urinary tract infections (UTIs). DETECT, applied as a diagnostic system, holds the potential to significantly improve the care of UTIs because it enables rapid identification of beta-lactamase-producing uropathogens directly from urine samples. The clinical feasibility of the technology has been demonstrated previously using clinical urine samples, first targeting a subset of beta-lactamases known as CTX-Ms. The proposed work aims to tune and optimize the first-generation system to offer a comprehensive diagnostic test that can accurately identify all of the clinically important beta-lactamases. This technology provides a simple, low-tech, and cost-effective way to inform patient treatment without the need of processing, urine sedimentation or centrifugation, or sophisticated instrumentation.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This award reflects NSF's statutory mission and has been deemed worthy of support through evaluation using the Foundation's intellectual merit and broader impacts review criteria.</AbstractNarration>
<MinAmdLetterDate>04/27/2020</MinAmdLetterDate>
<MaxAmdLetterDate>04/27/2020</MaxAmdLetterDate>
<ARRAAmount/>
<AwardID>2014629</AwardID>
<Investigator>
<FirstName>Angel</FirstName>
<LastName>Resendez</LastName>
<EmailAddress>aresendez@bioampdx.com</EmailAddress>
<StartDate>04/27/2020</StartDate>
<EndDate/>
<RoleCode>Principal Investigator</RoleCode>
</Investigator>
<Institution>
<Name>BioAmp Diagnostics, Inc.</Name>
<CityName>San Francisco</CityName>
<ZipCode>941096109</ZipCode>
<PhoneNumber>4086216332</PhoneNumber>
<StreetAddress>845 Sutter Street</StreetAddress>
<CountryName>United States</CountryName>
<StateName>California</StateName>
<StateCode>CA</StateCode>
</Institution>
<ProgramElement>
<Code>5371</Code>
<Text>SBIR Phase I</Text>
</ProgramElement>
<ProgramReference>
<Code>8038</Code>
<Text>Biotechnology</Text>
</ProgramReference>
</Award>
</rootTag>
