<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rootTag>
<Award>
<AwardTitle>A Strategic Plan Towards Developing a New Associate Degree Program in Radiation Health Physics at Navajo Technical University</AwardTitle>
<AwardEffectiveDate>03/01/2020</AwardEffectiveDate>
<AwardExpirationDate>10/31/2021</AwardExpirationDate>
<AwardTotalIntnAmount>49858.00</AwardTotalIntnAmount>
<AwardAmount>49858</AwardAmount>
<AwardInstrument>
<Value>Standard Grant</Value>
</AwardInstrument>
<Organization>
<Code>11060000</Code>
<Directorate>
<Abbreviation>EHR</Abbreviation>
<LongName>Direct For Education and Human Resources</LongName>
</Directorate>
<Division>
<Abbreviation>HRD</Abbreviation>
<LongName>Division Of Human Resource Development</LongName>
</Division>
</Organization>
<ProgramOfficer>
<SignBlockName>Lura Chase</SignBlockName>
</ProgramOfficer>
<AbstractNarration>A goal of the Tribal Colleges and Universities Program (TCUP) is to increase the science, technology, engineering and mathematics (STEM) instructional and research capacities of specific institutions of higher education that serve the Nation's indigenous students. Expanding the research capacity at these institutions expands the opportunities for students to pursue challenging, rewarding careers in STEM fields, provides for research studies in areas that may be locally relevant, and encourages a faculty community to look beyond the traditional classroom for intellectual and professional growth. This project aligns directly with that goal, allowing the institution's faculty and administrators to design and develop a comprehensive plan for improving and expanding STEM instruction. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Navajo Technical University (NTU) serves the Navajo Nation. NTU has partnered with the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC), and Chattanooga State Community College (CSCC) for developing its strategic plan towards developing a Radiation Health Physics Associate Degree program. NRC has an ongoing relationship with NTU and will bring in professionals in the field with rich experience and knowledge in training, program designing, course standardization, certifications and current practices in the radiation physics area. CSCC has successful experience in planning and implementing the radiation protection program. NTU has assembled a team that not only has immense experience in the field of radiation physics, but also has new program building experience.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This award reflects NSF's statutory mission and has been deemed worthy of support through evaluation using the Foundation's intellectual merit and broader impacts review criteria.</AbstractNarration>
<MinAmdLetterDate>02/10/2020</MinAmdLetterDate>
<MaxAmdLetterDate>02/10/2020</MaxAmdLetterDate>
<ARRAAmount/>
<AwardID>2016212</AwardID>
<Investigator>
<FirstName>Abraham</FirstName>
<LastName>Meles</LastName>
<EmailAddress>ameles@navajotech.edu</EmailAddress>
<StartDate>02/10/2020</StartDate>
<EndDate/>
<RoleCode>Co-Principal Investigator</RoleCode>
</Investigator>
<Investigator>
<FirstName>Abhishek</FirstName>
<LastName>RoyChowdhury</LastName>
<EmailAddress>aroychowdhury@navajotech.edu</EmailAddress>
<StartDate>02/10/2020</StartDate>
<EndDate/>
<RoleCode>Principal Investigator</RoleCode>
</Investigator>
<Investigator>
<FirstName>Steven</FirstName>
<LastName>Chischilly</LastName>
<EmailAddress>schischilly@navajotech.edu</EmailAddress>
<StartDate>02/10/2020</StartDate>
<EndDate/>
<RoleCode>Co-Principal Investigator</RoleCode>
</Investigator>
<Institution>
<Name>Navajo Technical University</Name>
<CityName>Crownpoint</CityName>
<ZipCode>873130849</ZipCode>
<PhoneNumber>5057864112</PhoneNumber>
<StreetAddress>LOWER POINT ROAD</StreetAddress>
<CountryName>United States</CountryName>
<StateName>New Mexico</StateName>
<StateCode>NM</StateCode>
</Institution>
<ProgramElement>
<Code>1744</Code>
<Text>Tribal College &amp; Univers Prog</Text>
</ProgramElement>
<ProgramReference>
<Code>9150</Code>
<Text>EXP PROG TO STIM COMP RES</Text>
</ProgramReference>
<Appropriation>
<Code>0420</Code>
</Appropriation>
</Award>
</rootTag>
