<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rootTag>
<Award>
<AwardTitle>SBP: Social Identities in the 21st Century</AwardTitle>
<AwardEffectiveDate>07/01/2020</AwardEffectiveDate>
<AwardExpirationDate>06/30/2022</AwardExpirationDate>
<AwardTotalIntnAmount>177774.00</AwardTotalIntnAmount>
<AwardAmount>177774</AwardAmount>
<AwardInstrument>
<Value>Continuing Grant</Value>
</AwardInstrument>
<Organization>
<Code>04050000</Code>
<Directorate>
<Abbreviation>SBE</Abbreviation>
<LongName>Direct For Social, Behav &amp; Economic Scie</LongName>
</Directorate>
<Division>
<Abbreviation>SES</Abbreviation>
<LongName>Divn Of Social and Economic Sciences</LongName>
</Division>
</Organization>
<ProgramOfficer>
<SignBlockName>Melanie Hughes</SignBlockName>
</ProgramOfficer>
<AbstractNarration>The rise of the use of “they” as a singular pronoun accompanies changes in some laws, while research about the people for whom this usage is relevant is still rare.  The existence of such people is already challenging law and culture in the United States, and in several states and countries, relevant legal categories have changed. This project will help us better understand how people who use the pronoun “they”  understand their own gender, their perceptions of what expectations accompany their identities, and the societal implications of them.  This research will provide insight into what kinds of social  and organizational policies are relevant to these recent developments. Findings will also provide guidance for policymakers and businesses regarding how possible policy changes may affect both these individuals and our society more generally.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This project analyzes social identity by interviewing  people regarding how they conceptualize their place in the gender structure. The project will recruit interviewees in three metropolitan areas--Chicago, Dallas, and Seattle-- because past research suggests that identities differ according to community. Interview respondents will be recruited locally by targeted Facebook ads, postings on appropriate online venues, and in face-to-face social groups. Interviews will focus on respondents’ views of social identities to understand how relevant definitions are shifting. Findings from the project will inform sociological theories regarding how identity operates in several realms of social life, as well as theories regarding social change in the definitions of social groups.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This award reflects NSF's statutory mission and has been deemed worthy of support through evaluation using the Foundation's intellectual merit and broader impacts review criteria.</AbstractNarration>
<MinAmdLetterDate>07/01/2020</MinAmdLetterDate>
<MaxAmdLetterDate>08/11/2020</MaxAmdLetterDate>
<ARRAAmount/>
<AwardID>2017361</AwardID>
<Investigator>
<FirstName>Barbara</FirstName>
<LastName>Risman</LastName>
<EmailAddress>brisman@uic.edu</EmailAddress>
<StartDate>07/01/2020</StartDate>
<EndDate/>
<RoleCode>Principal Investigator</RoleCode>
</Investigator>
<Investigator>
<FirstName>William</FirstName>
<LastName>Scarborough</LastName>
<EmailAddress>William.Scarborough@unt.edu</EmailAddress>
<StartDate>07/01/2020</StartDate>
<EndDate/>
<RoleCode>Co-Principal Investigator</RoleCode>
</Investigator>
<Institution>
<Name>University of Illinois at Chicago</Name>
<CityName>Chicago</CityName>
<ZipCode>606124305</ZipCode>
<PhoneNumber>3129962862</PhoneNumber>
<StreetAddress>809 S. Marshfield Avenue</StreetAddress>
<CountryName>United States</CountryName>
<StateName>Illinois</StateName>
<StateCode>IL</StateCode>
</Institution>
<ProgramElement>
<Code>110Y</Code>
<Text>SBP-Science of Broadening Part</Text>
</ProgramElement>
<ProgramElement>
<Code>1331</Code>
<Text>Sociology</Text>
</ProgramElement>
<ProgramReference>
<Code>8050</Code>
<Text>Science of Broadening Participation</Text>
</ProgramReference>
<ProgramReference>
<Code>9178</Code>
<Text>UNDERGRADUATE EDUCATION</Text>
</ProgramReference>
<ProgramReference>
<Code>9179</Code>
<Text>GRADUATE INVOLVEMENT</Text>
</ProgramReference>
<Appropriation>
<Code>0120</Code>
</Appropriation>
</Award>
</rootTag>
