<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rootTag>
<Award>
<AwardTitle>SBIR Phase II:  Extended depth imaging with optical coherence tomography (OCT)</AwardTitle>
<AwardEffectiveDate>09/15/2020</AwardEffectiveDate>
<AwardExpirationDate>08/31/2022</AwardExpirationDate>
<AwardTotalIntnAmount>999281.00</AwardTotalIntnAmount>
<AwardAmount>999281</AwardAmount>
<AwardInstrument>
<Value>Cooperative Agreement</Value>
</AwardInstrument>
<Organization>
<Code>07070000</Code>
<Directorate>
<Abbreviation>ENG</Abbreviation>
<LongName>Directorate For Engineering</LongName>
</Directorate>
<Division>
<Abbreviation>IIP</Abbreviation>
<LongName>Div Of Industrial Innovation &amp; Partnersh</LongName>
</Division>
</Organization>
<ProgramOfficer>
<SignBlockName>Henry Ahn</SignBlockName>
</ProgramOfficer>
<AbstractNarration>The broader impact/commercial potential of this Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) Phase II project is in the development of new optical imaging techniques for evaluating the health of skin, teeth and gums. Optical imaging uses light instead of X-rays to produce detailed images of tissues. It has not yet been widely applied for dental and dermatology applications because the light does not penetrate deeply enough into tissues to be useful, and these devices are prohibitively expensive to manufacture. This project will develop a a new imaging scheme that allows deeper penetration into tissues, providing more useful diagnostic information; and with current 3D manufacturing techniques, it could cost roughly ten times less than the current alternatives. This technology will enable new safe, affordable imaging processes.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) Phase II project advances translation of a novel optical technique, dual axis deep imaging optical coherence tomography (OCT), for clinical imaging of skin and teeth. Translation of OCT is advanced for retinal imaging but has not enjoyed the same success in other applications.  This project will create new instruments for dentistry and dermatology by demonstrating: 1) how dual axis OCT can penetrate more deeply in biological tissues using instruments designed for each application; and 2) the economic feasibility using 3D manufacturing and system design.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This award reflects NSF's statutory mission and has been deemed worthy of support through evaluation using the Foundation's intellectual merit and broader impacts review criteria.</AbstractNarration>
<MinAmdLetterDate>09/11/2020</MinAmdLetterDate>
<MaxAmdLetterDate>10/13/2020</MaxAmdLetterDate>
<ARRAAmount/>
<AwardID>2025988</AwardID>
<Investigator>
<FirstName>William</FirstName>
<LastName>Brown</LastName>
<EmailAddress>william.brown@lumedicasystems.com</EmailAddress>
<StartDate>09/11/2020</StartDate>
<EndDate/>
<RoleCode>Principal Investigator</RoleCode>
</Investigator>
<Institution>
<Name>Lumedica, Inc</Name>
<CityName>Durham</CityName>
<ZipCode>277011120</ZipCode>
<PhoneNumber>9193065414</PhoneNumber>
<StreetAddress>1312 Dollar Ave</StreetAddress>
<CountryName>United States</CountryName>
<StateName>North Carolina</StateName>
<StateCode>NC</StateCode>
</Institution>
<ProgramElement>
<Code>5373</Code>
<Text>SBIR Phase II</Text>
</ProgramElement>
<ProgramReference>
<Code>004E</Code>
<Text>BIOMEDICAL ENG AND DIAGNOSTICS</Text>
</ProgramReference>
<ProgramReference>
<Code>066E</Code>
<Text>INSTRUMENTATION &amp; DIAGNOSTICS</Text>
</ProgramReference>
<ProgramReference>
<Code>8038</Code>
<Text>Biotechnology</Text>
</ProgramReference>
<Appropriation>
<Code>0120</Code>
</Appropriation>
</Award>
</rootTag>
