<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rootTag>
<Award>
<AwardTitle>SBIR Phase I:  Development and assessment of a diagnostic platform for rapid identification of COVID-19 patients without using custom reagents</AwardTitle>
<AwardEffectiveDate>07/01/2020</AwardEffectiveDate>
<AwardExpirationDate>12/31/2020</AwardExpirationDate>
<AwardTotalIntnAmount>256000.00</AwardTotalIntnAmount>
<AwardAmount>256000</AwardAmount>
<AwardInstrument>
<Value>Standard Grant</Value>
</AwardInstrument>
<Organization>
<Code>07070000</Code>
<Directorate>
<Abbreviation>ENG</Abbreviation>
<LongName>Directorate For Engineering</LongName>
</Directorate>
<Division>
<Abbreviation>IIP</Abbreviation>
<LongName>Div Of Industrial Innovation &amp; Partnersh</LongName>
</Division>
</Organization>
<ProgramOfficer>
<SignBlockName>Henry Ahn</SignBlockName>
</ProgramOfficer>
<AbstractNarration>The broader impact/commercial potential of this Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) Phase I project is to deploy a diagnostic to rapidly and inexpensively detect COVID-19 infections. Beyond the short-term goal of identifying COVID-19 patients, the technology will lend strong support for real-time infection tracking nationally. The same hardware components of the diagnostic can be used to identify a wide variety of pathogens without custom reagents. The system will work with a cloud-based database and monitoring system to rapidly identify hotspots of increased pathogen activity, enabling faster response to new pathogens since no hardware-related development, manufacturing, and distribution are needed. Once a new pathogen?s fingerprint is obtained, it can be easily distributed to deployed instruments to enable immediately tracking of the new pathogen. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) Phase I project aims to develop a rapid diagnostic capable of detecting SARS-nCoV2 directly from sample matrices without the use of custom reagents (like DNA) or a cold supply chain. The approach isolates intact virus directly from the specimen with the help of a disposable cartridge and a syringe pump. The isolated virus is then identified using Fourier-Transform Infrared Spectrometry (FTIR). The proposed work leverages the differential response to mechanical stress between the virus and the components of a sample matrix. This differential response is used to selectively lyse only the sample matrix components, not the virus. The debris is subsequently separated from the virus by size-based separation methods such as filtration, enabling rapid isolation of a broad range of pathogens directly from the sample. FTIR is used to identify the isolated virus since pathogens exhibit unique spectral fingerprints in the infrared region. The proposed Phase I effort will develop the protocol for isolating and identifying intact virus and will demonstrate the performance with nasopharyngeal swab samples. The results will be compared against results from RT-PCR methods to assess comparability.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This award reflects NSF's statutory mission and has been deemed worthy of support through evaluation using the Foundation's intellectual merit and broader impacts review criteria.</AbstractNarration>
<MinAmdLetterDate>07/02/2020</MinAmdLetterDate>
<MaxAmdLetterDate>07/02/2020</MaxAmdLetterDate>
<ARRAAmount/>
<AwardID>2029745</AwardID>
<Investigator>
<FirstName>Rajesh</FirstName>
<LastName>Krishnamurthy</LastName>
<EmailAddress>rk@3idx.com</EmailAddress>
<StartDate>07/02/2020</StartDate>
<EndDate/>
<RoleCode>Principal Investigator</RoleCode>
</Investigator>
<Institution>
<Name>3I Diagnostics, Inc.</Name>
<CityName>Germantown</CityName>
<ZipCode>208764064</ZipCode>
<PhoneNumber>3015156380</PhoneNumber>
<StreetAddress>20271 Goldenrod Lane</StreetAddress>
<CountryName>United States</CountryName>
<StateName>Maryland</StateName>
<StateCode>MD</StateCode>
</Institution>
<ProgramElement>
<Code>5371</Code>
<Text>SBIR Phase I</Text>
</ProgramElement>
<ProgramReference>
<Code>096Z</Code>
<Text>COVID-19 Research</Text>
</ProgramReference>
<ProgramReference>
<Code>8038</Code>
<Text>Biotechnology</Text>
</ProgramReference>
</Award>
</rootTag>
