<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rootTag>
<Award>
<AwardTitle>Innovation Pathways to Data Careers</AwardTitle>
<AwardEffectiveDate>10/01/2020</AwardEffectiveDate>
<AwardExpirationDate>09/30/2023</AwardExpirationDate>
<AwardTotalIntnAmount>998849.00</AwardTotalIntnAmount>
<AwardAmount>998849</AwardAmount>
<AwardInstrument>
<Value>Standard Grant</Value>
</AwardInstrument>
<Organization>
<Code>05050000</Code>
<Directorate>
<Abbreviation>CSE</Abbreviation>
<LongName>Direct For Computer &amp; Info Scie &amp; Enginr</LongName>
</Directorate>
<Division>
<Abbreviation>CNS</Abbreviation>
<LongName>Division Of Computer and Network Systems</LongName>
</Division>
</Organization>
<ProgramOfficer>
<SignBlockName>Allyson Kennedy</SignBlockName>
</ProgramOfficer>
<AbstractNarration>The use of big data as a decision-driver has expanded into every scientific, industrial, and business enterprise. As fundamental proficiency in data analytics creeps into this broad range of traditional occupations, there is an increased need for data fluency and proficiency. From data literacy for all students, to big-data-enabled specialists, individuals skilled in the variety of tasks and duties required to collect, clean, and analyze massive data sets are in high demand. Through a collaboration of Burlington Public Schools, Education Development Center, and the Massachusetts Department of Elementary and Secondary Education, this project will develop, test, and institutionalize a K-12 pathway focused on data science and careers. Utilizing a Massachusetts-wide initiative known as Innovation Pathways, this project will accelerate the expansion of student access to, participation in, and successful completion of pathways that culminate in meaningful postsecondary and workforce credentials. Equitable access, guided academic pathways, enhanced student support, relevant connections to careers, and partnerships are central to the development of the Innovation Pathway, and have the potential to broaden the participation of students entering data-centric careers.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This proposal design, develop, test, and institutionalize an innovation pathway focused on data careers (IPDC). The RPP is an extension of prior NSF-funded computer science and data projects and leverages a Networked Improvement Community (NIC) approach that includes high school and community college educators and industry and community partners. The research questions are driven by practice needs and focus on (1) what it takes to interest and motivate students to persist on an IPDC, (2) what characteristics of an IPDC most contribute to the success of the IPDC, (3) what supports are needed for teachers and other stakeholders to successfully implement an IPDC, and (4) the role of industry in sustaining a successful IPDC. Working with project partners, three school systems/high schools (designated as “development sites”) will form an extended research/practice team. This team will design, develop, and test curriculum for a data module to be integrated into high school civics courses and pilot a Visualization+Data Course and a Python+Data course to complete the IPDC. Working with teacher leaders/facilitators from the development sites, five school systems/high schools (designated as “field test sites”) will participate in professional development during Years 2 and 3. They will integrate the Civics+Data module in Year 2 and the Visualization+Data course in Year 3 and commit to implement the Python+Data course in the year following the end date of this project. Research findings will be used to guide further development of Innovation Pathways funded by the Massachusetts Department of Elementary and Secondary Education.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This award reflects NSF's statutory mission and has been deemed worthy of support through evaluation using the Foundation's intellectual merit and broader impacts review criteria.</AbstractNarration>
<MinAmdLetterDate>09/02/2020</MinAmdLetterDate>
<MaxAmdLetterDate>10/14/2020</MaxAmdLetterDate>
<ARRAAmount/>
<AwardID>2031479</AwardID>
<Investigator>
<FirstName>Deborah</FirstName>
<LastName>Boisvert</LastName>
<EmailAddress>dboisvert@edc.org</EmailAddress>
<StartDate>09/02/2020</StartDate>
<EndDate/>
<RoleCode>Co-Principal Investigator</RoleCode>
</Investigator>
<Investigator>
<FirstName>Anne</FirstName>
<LastName>DeMallie</LastName>
<EmailAddress>ademallie@doe.mass.edu</EmailAddress>
<StartDate>09/02/2020</StartDate>
<EndDate/>
<RoleCode>Co-Principal Investigator</RoleCode>
</Investigator>
<Investigator>
<FirstName>Joyce</FirstName>
<LastName>Malyn-Smith</LastName>
<EmailAddress>Jmalynsmith@edc.org</EmailAddress>
<StartDate>09/02/2020</StartDate>
<EndDate/>
<RoleCode>Principal Investigator</RoleCode>
</Investigator>
<Institution>
<Name>Education Development Center</Name>
<CityName>Waltham</CityName>
<ZipCode>024538313</ZipCode>
<PhoneNumber>6176182227</PhoneNumber>
<StreetAddress>43 Foundry Avenue</StreetAddress>
<CountryName>United States</CountryName>
<StateName>Massachusetts</StateName>
<StateCode>MA</StateCode>
</Institution>
<ProgramElement>
<Code>134Y</Code>
<Text>CSforAll-Computer Sci for All</Text>
</ProgramElement>
<ProgramReference>
<Code>023Z</Code>
<Text>Computer Science for All (CS for All)</Text>
</ProgramReference>
<Appropriation>
<Code>0120</Code>
</Appropriation>
</Award>
</rootTag>
